windowsonitaly.com 2018-10-22

# Privacy - Windows on Italy

## Privacy Policy

Effective date: May 14, 2018

Welcome to Windows on Italy’s website, which is property of Windows on Italy Srl (hereinafter “Windows on Italy"), Data Controller based in Piazza IV Novembre, 7, 20124, Milan. The email address of our Privacy Officer is [privacy.officer@windowsoneurope.com](mailto:privacy.officer@windowsoneurope.com).

Your privacy is very important to us and therefore we want to inform you about how we collect and use your information.  
Our company has always paid particular attention to the processing and protection of personal data of its Customers, Users, Suppliers, Collaborators, and all those with whom it comes into contact. For this reason, in order to ensure maximum compliance with the law, Legislative Decree of June 30, 2003 n. 196 and the EU Regulation 2016/679, Windows on Italy has adopted a suitable Privacy Organizational Model.

The Code and the Regulation in question requests that those who carry out processing of personal data are required to inform the person involved on what data is processed and regarding certain elements: it must be lawfully and transparently done, protecting your privacy and your rights. In accordance with the provisions of Article 13 of Legislative Decree 196/2003 and Articles 13 and 14 of EU Regulation 2016/679, we provide the following information.

 **Why?**  
This page describes how we manage our website in relation to the processing of its users’ personal data.

This is information that is made available to those who interact with Windows on Italy's web services, accessible electronically at:  _http://www.windowsonitaly.com_.  

This information is provided only for Windows on Italy’s website and is not intended for other websites that may be consulted by the user through links.

This information is also based on the [Recommendation n. 2/2001](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/garante/doc.jsp?ID=1609845) that the European authorities created for the protection of personal data, established by [art. 29 of the directive n. 95/46/CE](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/garante/document?ID=432175), adopted on May 17, 2001 to identify certain minimum requirements for the collection of personal data online, and, in particular, the methods, timing, and nature of the information that the data controllers must provide to the users when they connect to websites, regardless of the purpose of the connection.

 **#InShort**  
This privacy statement describes our privacy practices, what information we collect about our visitors and users, how we collect them, what we do with them, how we protect them and the rights of the User with respect to their information.

 **What information do we collect?**  
 **Navigation data**  
The computer systems and software procedures used to operate this website acquire, during its normal operation, some personal data whose transmission is implicit in the use of Internet communication protocols.  
This is information that is not collected to be associated with identified interested parties, but which by its very nature could, through processing and association with data held by third parties, allow users to be identified.  
This category of data includes IP addresses or domain names of the computers used by users connecting to the website, the addresses in the Uniform Resource Identifier (URI) notation of the requested resources, the time of the request, the method used to submit the request to the server, the size of the file obtained in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the response given by the server (success, error, etc.) and other parameters relating to the operating system and the user’s computer environment.  
This data is used for the sole purpose of obtaining anonymous statistical information on the use of the website and to check its correct functioning, and are deleted immediately after processing. The data could be used to ascertain responsibility in case of hypothetical computer crimes to the website.

 **Cookies**  
Our Cookie Policy can be seen _[here](http://www.windowsonitaly.com/content/cookie-policy)._

Data provided voluntarily by the user  
The optional, explicit, and voluntary sending of emails to the addresses indicated on this site or the completion of specific forms, involves the subsequent acquisition of the sender’s address and personal data necessary to respond to requests and / or to provide the requested services, as well as any other personal data included in the message (and in the attachments thereto) or in the appropriate forms.  
The data will be processed in computer and telematic modes, to respond to requests and / or provide the requested service.

 **#InShort**  
We collect two types of information: Personal Information (which can be used to uniquely identify an individual) and Non-Personal Information (which does not allow identification).

We collect information about our users, visitors, and job applicants.

 **Why do we collect this information?**  
We collect such information for the following purposes:  
✓ To respond to your requests;  
✓ To send you our Newsletter;  
✓ To provide and manage our Services;  
✓ To further develop, customize, and improve our Services based on the preferences, experiences, and common or personal difficulties of Visitors and Users;  
✓ Provide our Customers with customer assistance and continuous technical support;  
✓ Consider the candidacy of Candidates for recruitment  
✓ Comply with legal obligations.

 **#InShort**  
We collect and use information to provide our services and make them better and safer.

In addition, we collect and use this information to contact our visitors, users, and candidates for recruitment and to comply with applicable laws.

 **Who do we share your information with?**  
Windows on Italy may share your Information with third parties (or otherwise grant them access) only in the following ways and in the following cases:

 **Third party services  **  
Windows on Italy collaborates with a number of selected service providers, whose services and solutions are integrated with ours, to facilitate and improve them.  
These are hosting and co-location server services, communications, IT security services, billing and payment processing services, marketing services, fraud detection and prevention services, web analysis, newsletter distribution and monitoring services, session registration and remote access services, content providers, and our legal and financial advisors.  
Such Third Party Services may receive or otherwise have access to the Personal Information of our Users, in its entirety or in part, depending on its particular role and purpose aimed at facilitating and improving our Services and may use them only for such purposes.

 **Compliance with legal obligations**  
Windows on Italy may disclose or otherwise grant access to the User’s Personal Information to others by virtue of legal obligation, such as a court summons, a judicial proceeding, a search warrant, a court order, or under applicable law, if it believes in good faith that this conduct is required by law, with or without prior notice to the User.

 **Social media functionality**  
Our website may include certain Social Media features and widgets, such as the “Like Facebook” button, the “Share” button or other interactive mini-programs. These Social Media Capabilities can collect information such as the IP address of the User or page you are visiting on our Site and may release a cookie to allow proper operation.  
The Social Media features are hosted by third parties. The User’s interactions with these third parties are governed by their information and not by our own.

 **Companies related to  Windows on Italy   
**We may share Personal Information internally with companies in our group, for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Furthermore, in the event of a change in the corporate control structure of Windows on Italy Srl or an affiliate thereof, for example through the merger, acquisition, or purchase of substantially all of its assets, the User’s Personal Information may be shared with the parties involved in this event.

If we believe in good faith that this change in the corporate control structure could substantially affect the User’s Personal Information stored with us, we will inform the User by email and / or we will communicate this on our Website and the choices available to the User in relation to their Personal Information.

 **#InShort**

We may share information about our visitors and users with third parties, including certain service providers and law enforcement officials.  
The information can be shared only in compliance with this policy.

 **When can we contact you?**  
 **Promotional content**  
By subscribing to our newsletter and providing us with an email address or other contact information, you expressly agree to receive promotional content by email.  
If you do not wish to receive such promotional messages, you may notify Windows on Italy at any time or follow the cancellation or unsubscribe instructions contained in the promotional communications received.

 **#InShort**  
With explicit consent, the User can receive our messages and promotional content.  
The User can choose not to receive promotional messages simply by contacting us or using our cancellation options.

 **How long do we keep your information?**  
We may retain the User’s Personal Information as long as necessary for the provision of our Services.  
We may continue to retain such Personal Information even after the termination of the use of any particular Service, to the extent that it is reasonably necessary to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes concerning our Users, prevent fraud and abuse, respect the contracts signed, and / or protect our legitimate interests.

 **#InShort**  
We may retain your information as long as necessary for the provision of our Services and for as long as necessary (for example, to comply with a legal obligation or to protect our interests).

 **Your rights and how to contact us**  
We remind you that you have the right, at any time, to obtain confirmation of the existence or absence of your personal data treated by us and to know its content and origin, verify its accuracy, or request its integration, updating, rectification.

You also have the right to request the cancellation, transformation into an anonymous form, or blocking of data processed in violation of the law, as well as to request the limitation, or oppose in any case, for legitimate reasons, to its treatment.

Requests should be addressed:  
✓ via email, to our Privacy Officer: privacy.officer@windowsoneurope.com  
✓ or via mail to: Privacy Officer - Windows on Italy Srl, Piazza IV novembre, 7, 20124, Milan.  

 **#InShort**

The User and all interested parties can ask by email or letter to access the personal data processed by us, and ask for its correction or cancellation.

We will respond to requests within a reasonable time frame and, in any case, no later than 30 days from receipt.
